We've talked about how to evaluate
我们已经介绍了怎样评价一个学习算法
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
learning algorithms, talked about model selection,
我们讨论了模型选择问题
talked a lot about bias and variance.
偏差和方差的问题
So how does this help us figure
那么这些诊断法则怎样帮助我们弄清
out what are potentially fruitful,
哪些方法有助于
potentially not fruitful things to
改进学习算法的效果
try to do to improve the performance of a learning algorithm.
哪些又是徒劳的呢
Let's go back to our original
让我们再次回到最开始的例子
motivating example and go for the result.
在那里寻找答案
So here is our earlier example
这就是我们之前的例子
of maybe having fit regularized
我们试图用正则化的线性回归拟合模型
linear regression and finding that it doesn't work as well as we're hoping.
并评价该算法是否达到预期效果
We said that we had this menu of options.
我们提出了如下这些选择
So is there some way to
那么到底有没有某种方法
figure out which of these might be fruitful options?
能够明确指出以上哪些方法有效呢
The first thing all of this
第一种可供选择的方法
was getting more training examples.
是使用更多的训练集数据
What this is good for,
这种方法对于高方差的情况
is this helps to fix high variance.
是有帮助的
And concretely, if you instead
也就是说
have a high bias problem and
如果你的模型不处于高方差问题
don't have any variance problem, then
而是高偏差的时候
we saw in the previous video
那么通过前面的视频
that getting more training examples,
我们已经知道 获取更多的训练集数据
while maybe just isn't going to help much at all.
并不会有太明显的帮助
So the first option is useful
所以 要选择第一种方法
only if you, say, plot
你应该先画出
the learning curves and figure
学习曲线
out that you have at least
然后看出你的模型
a bit of a variance, meaning that
应该至少有那么一点方差问题
the cross-validation error is, you know,
也就是说你的交叉验证集误差
quite a bit bigger than your training set error.
应该比训练集误差大一点
How about trying a smaller set of features?
第二种方法情况又如何呢
Well, trying a smaller
第二种方法是
set of features, that's again
少选几种特征
something that fixes high variance.
这同样是对高方差时有效
And in other words, if you figure
换句话说
out, by looking at learning curves
如果你通过绘制学习曲线
or something else that you used,
或者别的什么方法
that have a high bias
看出你的模型处于高偏差问题
problem; then for goodness
那么切记
sakes, don't waste your time
千万不要浪费时间
trying to carefully select out
试图从已有的特征中
a smaller set of features to use.
挑出一小部分来使用
Because if you have a high bias problem, using
因为你已经发现高偏差的问题了
fewer features is not going to help.
使用更少的特征仍然无济于事
Whereas in contrast, if you
反过来 如果你发现
look at the learning curves or something
从你的学习曲线
else you figure out that you
或者别的某种诊断图中
have a high variance problem, then,
你看出了高方差的问题
indeed trying to select
那么恭喜你
out a smaller set of features,
花点时间挑选出一小部分合适的特征吧
that might indeed be a very good use of your time.
这是把时间用在了刀刃上
How about trying to get additional
方法三 选用更多的特征又如何呢
features, adding features, usually,
通常来讲
not always, but usually we
不是所有时候都适用
think of this as a solution
但通常来说 增加特征数
for fixing high bias problems.
是解决高偏差问题的法宝
So if you are adding extra
所以如果你要增加
features it's usually because
更多的特征时
your current hypothesis is too
一般是由于你现有的
simple, and so we want
假设函数太简单
to try to get additional features to
因此我们才决定增加一些
make our hypothesis better able
别的特征来让假设函数
to fit the training set. And
更好地拟合训练集
similarly, adding polynomial features;
接下来 类似地
this is another way of adding
增加更多的多项式特征
features and so there
这实际上也是属于增加特征
is another way to try
因此也是用于
to fix the high bias problem.
修正高偏差问题
And, if concretely if
具体来说
your learning curves show you
如果你画出的学习曲线告诉你
that you still have a high
你还是处于高方差问题
variance problem, then, you know, again this
那么采取这种方法
is maybe a less good use of your time.
依然是浪费时间
And finally, decreasing and increasing lambda.
最后 增大和减小lambda
This are quick and easy to try,
这种方法尝试起来最方便
I guess these are less likely to
我想尝试这个方法
be a waste of, you know, many months of your life.
不至于花费你几个月时间
But decreasing lambda, you
但我们已经知道
already know fixes high bias.
减小lambda可以修正高偏差
In case this isn't clear to
如果我说的你还不清楚的话
you, you know, I do encourage
我建议你暂停视频
you to pause the video and think through this that
仔细回忆一下
convince yourself that decreasing lambda
减小lambda的值
helps fix high bias, whereas increasing
有助于修正高偏差
lambda fixes high variance.
而增大lambda的值解决高方差
And if you aren't sure why
如果你确实不明白
this is the case, do
为什么是这样的话
pause the video and make
那就暂停一下好好想想
sure you can convince yourself that this is the case.
直到真的弄清楚这个道理
Or take a look at the curves
或者看看
that we were plotting at the
上一节视频最后
end of the previous video and
我们绘制的学习曲线
try to make sure you understand
试着理解清楚
why these are the case.
为什么是我说的那样
Finally, let us take everything
最后 我们回顾一下
we have learned and relate it back
这几节课介绍的这些内容
to neural networks and so,
并且看看它们和神经网络的联系
here is some practical
我想介绍一些
advice for how I usually
很实用的经验或建议
choose the architecture or the
这些来自于我平时为神经网络模型
connectivity pattern of the neural networks I use.
选择结构或者连接形式的一些技巧
So, if you are fitting
当你在进行神经网络拟合的时候
a neural network, one option would
你可以选择一种
be to fit, say, a pretty
比如说
small neural network with you know, relatively
一个相对比较简单的神经网络模型
few hidden units, maybe just
相对来讲 隐藏单元比较少
one hidden unit. If you're fitting
或者甚至只有一个隐藏单元
a neural network, one option would
如果你要进行神经网络的拟合
be to fit a relatively small
其中一个选择是
neural network with, say,
选用一个相对简单的网络结构
relatively few, maybe only one
比如说只有一个
hidden layer and maybe
隐藏层
only a relatively few number
或者可能相对来讲
of hidden units.
比较少的隐藏单元
So, a network like this might have relatively
因此像这样的一个简单的神经网络
few parameters and be more prone to underfitting.
参数就不会很多 并且很容易出现欠拟合
The main advantage of these small
这种比较小型的神经网络
neural networks is that the computation will be cheaper.
其最大优势在于计算量较小
An alternative would be to
与之相对的另一种情况
fit a, maybe relatively large
是相对较大型的神经网络结构
neural network with either more
隐藏层单元会比较多
hidden units--there's a lot
比如每一层中的隐藏单元数很多
of hidden in one there--or with more hidden layers.
或者有很多个隐藏层
And so these neural networks tend
因此这种比较复杂的神经网络
to have more parameters and therefore be more prone to overfitting.
参数一般较多 也更容易出现过拟合
One disadvantage, often not a
这种结构的一大劣势
major one but something to
也许不是主要的 但还是需要考虑
think about, is that if you have
那就是当网络中的
a large number of neurons
神经元数量很多的时候
in your network, then it can
这种结构会显得
be more computationally expensive.
计算量较为庞大
Although within reason, this is often hopefully not a huge problem.
虽然有这个情况 但通常来讲不成问题
The main potential problem of
这种大型网络结构最主要的问题
these much larger neural networks is that it could be more prone to overfitting
还是它更容易出现过拟合现象
and it turns out if you're applying neural
事实上 如果你经常应用神经网络
network very often using
特别是大型神经网络的话
a large neural network often it's actually the larger, the better
你就会发现越大型的网络性能越好
but if it's overfitting, you can
但如果发生了过拟合
then use regularization to address
你可以使用正则化的方法
overfitting, usually using
来修正过拟合
a larger neural network by using
一般来说 使用一个大型的神经网络
regularization to address is
并使用正则化来修正过拟合问题
overfitting that's often more
通常比使用一个小型的神经网络
effective than using a smaller neural network.
效果更好
And the main possible disadvantage is
但主要可能出现的一大问题
that it can be more computationally expensive.
就是计算量相对较大
And finally, one of the other decisions is, say,
最后 你还需要选择的
the number of hidden layers you want to have, right?
是隐藏层的层数
So, do you want
你是应该用一个
one hidden layer or do
隐藏层呢
you want three hidden layers, as
还是应该用三个呢 就像我们这里画的
we've shown here, or do you want two hidden layers?
或者还是用两个隐藏层呢
And usually, as I
通常来说
think I said in the previous
正如我在前面的视频中讲过的
video, using a single
默认的情况是
hidden layer is a reasonable default, but
使用一个隐藏层是比较合理的选择
if you want to choose the
但是如果你想要选择
number of hidden layers, one
一个最合适的隐藏层层数
other thing you can try is
你也可以试试
find yourself a training cross-validation,
把数据分割为训练集 验证集
and test set split and try
和测试集 然后试试使用
training neural networks with one
一个隐藏层的神经网络来训练模型
hidden layer or two hidden
然后试试两个 三个隐藏层
layers or three hidden layers and
以此类推
see which of those neural
然后看看哪个神经网络
networks performs best on the cross-validation sets.
在交叉验证集上表现得最理想
You take your three neural networks
也就是说 你得到了三个神经网络模型
with one, two and three hidden
分别有一个 两个 三个隐藏层
layers, and compute the
然后你对每一个模型
cross validation error at Jcv
都用交叉验证集数据进行测试
and all of
算出三种情况下的
them and use that to
交叉验证集误差Jcv
select which of these
然后选出你认为最好的
is you think the best neural network.
神经网络结构
So, that's it for
好的 以上就是我们介绍的
bias and variance and ways
偏差和方差问题
like learning curves, who tried to diagnose these problems.
以及如学习曲线这样的诊断法
As far as what
在改进学习算法的表现时
you think is implied, for one
你可以充分运用
might be truthful or not
以上这些内容来判断
truthful things to try
哪些途径是有帮助的
to improve the performance of a learning algorithm.
哪些方法是无意义的
If you understood the contents
如果你理解了以上几节视频中
of the last few videos and if
介绍的内容
you apply them you actually
并且懂得如何运用
be much more effective already and
那么你已经很厉害了
getting learning algorithms to work on problems
你也能像硅谷的
and even a large fraction,
大部分机器学习专家一样
maybe the majority of practitioners
他们每天的工作就是
of machine learning here in
有效地使用这些学习算法
Silicon Valley today doing these things as their full-time jobs.
来解决众多具体的问题
So I hope that these
我希望这几节中
pieces of advice
提到的一些技巧
on by experience in diagnostics
关于方差 偏差 以及学习曲线为代表的诊断法
will help you to much effectively
能够真正帮助你更有效率地
and powerfully apply learning and
应用机器学习
get them to work very well.
让它们高效地工作